Finding Aid for School of Dentistry (University of Michigan) Records, 1873-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Administration, 1899-1999
  - Files, circa 1918-circa 1985
    - Dean's Files
      - Bunting, Russell W.
        - Correspondence
          - Faculty and Departments, 1920-1948 (Box 5)
          - Ohio State University, 1942-1948 (Box 5)
          - Organizations, 1936-1937; 1940-1948 (Box 5)
            (except 1943)
          - Gerald D. Timmons, Temple University, 1938-1950 (Box 5)
          - United States Government, 1939-1950 (Box 5)
          - United States Navy and Army, 1942-1949 (Box 5)
          - United States Public Health Service, 1941-1950 (Box 5)
          - Universities, 1935-1950 (Box 5)
            (except 1936-1943)
          - University of Texas, 1938-1949 (Box 5)
          - University of Toronto, 1937-1949 (Box 5)
          - Veteran's Administration, 1943-1949 (Box 5)
          - War Manpower Commission Procurement and Assignment Service, 1942-1945 (Box 5)
          - W. D. Miller Memorial, 1939-1940 (Box 5)
          - Miscellaneous, 1939-1950 (Box 5)
        - United States Navy V-12 Program, 1945 (Box 5)
      - Jeserich, Paul H.
        - Biography, undated (Box 5)
        - Correspondence
          - Congress of the United States, 1954; 1961; 1965 (Box 5)
          - United States Army, 1950-1953 (Box 5)
          - Universities, 1950-1958; 1961 (Box 5)
            (except 1953, 1954 and 1957)
          - Miscellaneous, 1950-1965 (Box 5)
      - Mann, William R.
        - Biographical Information, undated (Box 5)
        - Correspondence
          - Administration, 1950; 1960-1969; 1970-1979 (Box 5)
          - Elementary School Growth Data, 1971; 1981 (Box 5)
          - Organizations, 1951-1952; 1955; 1962-1969; 1970-1971 (Box 5)
          - Pauly, Raymond, 1972-1981 (Box 5)
          - Restrepo, Oscar J., 1958-1966 (Box 5)
          - Thompson, Morris J., 1952-1954 (Box 5)
          - United States Government
            - 1965-1967 (Box 5)
            - 1970, 1974; 1978 (Box 5)
          - United States Veterans Administration, 1950-1972 (Box 5)
          - Universities, 1960-1963; 1967-1969; 1971-1974 (Box 5)
          - Vice President for Academic Affairs, 1963-1967 (Box 5)
          - Vice President for States Relations, 1971-1977 (Box 6)
          - Virginia State Dental Association, 1962-1963 (Box 6)
          - Washtenaw County Community College, 1966-1971 (Box 6)
          - Ypsilanti State Hospital, 1969-1970 (Box 6)
          - Miscellaneous, 1953; 1957; 1960-1967; 1971-1980 (Box 6)
        - Publications and Speeches, 1959-1967 (Box 6)
      - Ward, Marcus L.
        - Banquet Programs, 1935-1939 (Box 6)
        - Correspondence
          - Administration
            - Curriculum, 1920-1929; 1932-1935 (Box 6)
            - Dental Building Maintenance, 1922-1928; 1930; 1932 (Box 6)
              (except 1925-1926)
            - Dental Handpieces, 1927-1929 (Box 6)
            - Miscellaneous, 1922-1926; 1940-1941; 1952 (Box 6)
          - Dental Faculties Association of American Universities, 1918-1921 (Box 6)
          - Gies, William, 1934 (Box 6)
          - Government, 1927-1928; 1930; 1933; 1944 (Box 6)
          - Organizations, 1923; 1927-1929; 1930; 1933 (Box 6)
          - Universities, 1918; 1926-1933; 1940 (Box 6)
            (except 1927)
        - Speeches and Publications, undated (Box 6)
  - Files, circa 1880-1982
    - Finances
      - Clinic Fee Proposal, 1974-1975 (Box 7)
      - Clinical Fees, 1969-1983 (Box 7)
      - Dental Supplies Purchases and Orders, 1880-1882 (Box 7)
      - Operating Costs, 1930-1942 (Box 7)
      - Program Budget, 1973-1976 (Box 7)
    - Regents
      - Correspondence, 1941; 1947 (Box 7)
      - Communications, 1916-1962; 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Reports
      - A Study of the Dentogenic Concept of Dental Esthetics and Dynesthetics, 1957 (Box 7)
      - Continuing Education (Box 8)
        - Financial Reports, 1977-1982; 2 folders (Box 8)
        - Miscellaneous Reports, 1978-1981 (Box 8)
      - Dental Manpower Supply in Michigan, 1972; 1980-1981; 2 folders (Box 8)
      - Flint Dental Clinic Reports, 1918-1922 (Box 8)
      - Fluid Turbine Dental Engine Studies, 1951 (Box 8)
      - Health Personnel Task Force, 1975 (Box 8)
      - Maxillo Facial Prosthetic Section Proposal, 1965 (Box 8)
      - Orthodontic Clinic Accounts Receivable Procedure, 1966-1968 (Box 8)
      - Periodic Health Appraisal Unit: Report of Activities of the First Nine Years, 1966 (Box 8)
      - Post Construction Site Visit, 1971 (Box 8)
      - Prosthodontic Workshop, 1970-1972 (Box 8)
      - Report on Preventive Education Clinic, 1977 (Box 8)
      - Study on Traumatic Effects of Rotating Dental Instruments, 1952-1955 (Box 8)
      - Workshops Reports, 1957-1959 (Box 8)
    - Wayne County General Hospital, 1963-1973 (Box 8)
    - W. K. Kellogg Foundation Institute
      - American Dental Association Council on Dental Education, 1956 (Box 8)
      - Blackerby, Philip E.
        - Correspondence, 1939-1971 (Box 8)
      - Blueprints, 1938-1944 (Box 8)
      - Dedication and Homecoming, 1940 (Box 8)
      - Dental Advisory Committee, 1964-1967 (Box 8)
      - Evaluation of Dental Education 190, 191 and 192, 1957 (Box 8)
      - Field Program for Senior Dental Students, 1940 (Box 8)
      - Graduate Program in Dental Hygiene, 1963-1969 (Box 8)
      - Interamerican Course in Dentistry, 1942-1946; 3 folders (Box 8)
      - Latin American Advisory Committee
        - Correspondence, 1963-1967 (Box 8)
        - Field Trips, 1964-1967 (Box 8)
        - Minutes, 1964-1967 (Box 8)
        - Reports, 1964-1967 (Box 9)
      - Miscellaneous, 1958-1972 (Box 9)
      - Morris, Emory William, 1962-1974 (Box 9)
      - Orthodontic Workshops, 1956-1958 (Box 9)
      - Planning Study of a Maximal Ambulatory Care Center, 1965 (Box 9)
      - Reports, 1944-1946 (Box 9)
  - Files, 1911-1999
    - Administrative Information
      - Admissions Statistics (Box 14)
      - Dental History, 2 folders (Box 14)
      - Objectives, Resolutions, Goals (Box 14)
      - Yonsei University
        - Correspondence (sistership) (Box 14)
        - Signed Agreements (sistership) (Box 14)
    - Committees
      - Ad Hoc Committees
        - Energy Utilization and Conservation (Box 14)
        - Faculty Development, 1981-1983 (Box 14)
        - General Practice Residency Program, 1981-1983 (Box 14)
        - Policy for Restricted Gifts, 1982-1983 (Box 14)
        - Television Tapes, 1982-1985 (Box 14)
      - Admissions Committee, 1974-1986 (Box 14)
      - Animal Care Committee, 1964-1986 (Box 14)
      - Annual Reports, 1985 (Box 14)
      - Budget Priorities Committee, 2 folders (Box 14)
      - Clinic Coordinating Committee, 1962-1969 (Box 14)
      - Committee on Computer Utilization, 1982-1986 (Box 14)
      - Committee on Continuing Education, 1981-1986 (Box 14)
      - Advisory Committee to Director of Clinics, 1982-1986
        - Committee to Review Counseling (Box 14)
        - Comprehensive Care Panel, 1983-1984 (Box 14)
        - Criteria for Evaluation and Grading Committee (Box 14)
      - Curriculum Committee, 1962-1969; 2 folders (Box 15)
      - Development and Planning Committee, 1970-1980 (Box 15)
      - Dress and Appearance Committee, 1973-1981 (Box 15)
      - Drug Committee, 1973-1981 (Box 15)
      - Editorial Board Committee, 1982-1983 (Box 15)
      - Educational Affairs Committee (formerly Curriculum Committee), 1981-1986 (Box 15)
      - Elective Time Committee, 1982-1983 (Box 15)
      - Examining and Grading Committee, 1969-1971 (Box 15)
      - Executive Committee
        - Meetings
          - 1911-1931 (Box 15)
          - 1931-1936 (Box 15)
          - 1936-1938 (Box 15)
          - 1938-1947 (Box 15)
          - 1947-1962 (Box 15)
          - 1970 (Box 15)
          - 1971 (Box 15)
          - 1972 (Box 15)
          - 1973 (Box 15)
          - 1974 (Box 15)
          - 1975 (Box 15)
          - 1976 (Box 15)
          - 1977 (Box 15)
          - 1978 (Box 15)
          - 1979 (Box 15)
          - 1980 (Box 15)
          - 1981 (Box 16)
          - 1981-1982 (Box 16)
          - 1982-1983, 5 folders (Box 16)
          - 1984, 2 folders (Box 16)
          - 1985, 2 folders (Box 16)
          - 1986, 2 folders (Box 16)
          - 1987, 3 folders (Box 17)
          - 1988, 3 folders (Box 17)
          - 1989, 4 folders (Box 17)
          - 1990, 4 folders (Box 17)
          - 1991, 5 folders (Box 18)
          - 1992, 7 folders (Box 18)
          - 1993, 7 folders (Box 19)
          - 1994, 9 folders (Box 19)
          - 1995, 9 folders (Box 20)
          - 1996, 6 folders (Box 20)
          - 1996, 4 folders (Box 21)
          - 1997, 11 folders (Box 21)
        - Meetings (cont.)
          - 1997, 3 folders (Box 23)
          - 1998, 9 folders (Box 23)
          - 1999, 4 folders (Box 23)
          - 1999, 3 folders (Box 24)
        - Retreats
          - 1986 (Box 24)
          - 1989 (Box 24)
          - 1993 (Box 24)
        - Votes
          - Pre-1986 (Box 24)
          - 1986 (Box 24)
          - 1988 (Box 24)
          - Policies (Box 24)
        - Student Appeals (Box 24)
        - Summaries
          - 1975-1976 (Box 24)
          - 1977-1980 (Box 24)
          - 1980-1983 (Box 24)
          - 1984-1986 (Box 24)
          - 1987-1989 (Box 24)
          - 1990-1995 (Box 24)
      - Financial Development Committee (Box 24)
      - Graduate Studies Committee
        - 1962-1969 (Box 24)
        - 1969-1970 (Box 24)
        - 1972-1976 (Box 24)
        - 1976-1982 (Box 24)
        - 1983-1987 (Box 24)
      - Guest Relations Program Leader Manual (Box 24)
      - Homecoming Committee
        - 1969-1979 (Box 24)
        - 1986-1989 (Box 24)
      - Honor Code/System (Box 24)
      - Infection Control Committee, 1981-1986 (Box 24)
      - Library Committee, 1962-1991 (Box 24)
      - New Products Committee, 1973-1981 (Box 24)
      - Oral Biology Committee, 1962-1963; 1966-1967 (Box 24)
      - Photography Committee, 1962-1965 (Box 24)
      - Preventive Education Clinic, 1978-1986 (Box 24)
      - Public Information Office, 1965-1966 (Box 24)
      - Record Committee, 1966-1969 (Box 24)
      - Radiation Policy Committee, 1985-1987 (Box 24)
      - Research Committee
        - 1962-1979 (Box 24)
        - 1979-1986 (Box 24)
      - Research Involving Human Subjects Committee
        - 1969-1980 (Box 24)
        - 1980-1987 (Box 24)
      - Resuscitation and Emergency Procedures Committee, 1969-1986 (Box 25)
      - Search Committee for the Dean, 1980-1981
        - Correspondence (Box 25)
        - Interviews (Box 25)
        - Minutes and Guidelines (Box 25)
        - People, Agendas, Correspondence (Box 25)
        - Regents Meeting (Box 25)
      - Strategic Planning Committee (Box 25)
      - Student Affairs Committee, 1964-1986 (Box 25)
      - Student Research Committee, 1982-1986 (Box 25)
      - Student Table Clinic Committee
        - 1965-1982 (Box 25)
        - 1982-1990 (Box 25)
      - Teaching Committee, 1962-1969 (Box 25)
      - Transition Committee
        - Correspondence (Box 25)
        - Correspondence with James Duderstadt (Box 25)
        - Dental Hygiene Committee (Box 25)
        - Final Report (Box 25)
        - Interview Meetings, July 23 and 24, 1987 (Box 25)
        - Preliminary Strategies for Next 5 Years (Box 25)
        - Position Descriptions and Structure Charts (Box 25)
        - Progress Report, 2 folders (Box 25)
        - Responses to Alumni Letter, July 31, 1987 (Box 25)
        - Undergraduate Dental Curriculum Plans (Box 25)
    - Finances
      - Conference, 1978-1980 (Box 26)
      - Reports, 1980 (Box 26)
      - Requests, 1971-1974; 1977-1980; 2 folders (Box 26)
      - Building Statistics (Box 26)
      - Funding by Department (Box 26)
      - Planning Activities, 1963 (Box 26)
      - Policies on Instructional Materials, 1975 (Box 26)
    - Deans' Files
      - Christiansen
        - Correspondence, 2 folders (Box 26)
        - Kellogg Building (Box 26)
      - Doerr
        - Enrollment Reductions (Box 26)
        - Guidelines for Determining Merit (Box 26)
      - Kotowicz
        - Chairs Retreat Materials, 1989 (Box 26)
      - Machen
        - Biographical Materials (Box 26)
        - Bylaws Revision, 1990 (Box 26)
        - Correspondence (Box 26)
        - Domestic Partnerships, 2 folders (Box 26)
        - Health Care Reform (Box 26)
        - Newspaper Clippings (Box 26)
        - Presidential Committee to Study Accreditation, 2 folders (Box 27)
        - Publications (Box 27)
        - Speeches and Presentations (Box 27)
        - University of Utah (Box 27)
      - Mann
        - Copyright Law Revision (Box 27)
        - Correspondence (Box 27)
        - Memo of Understanding (Box 27)
    - Evaluations
      - Prevention and Healthcare, 1990 (Box 28)
      - Faculty/Chair Review, 1994; 3 folders (Box 28)
      - Chair Reviews, 1995 (Box 28)
      - Faculty Reviews, 1995 (Box 28)
      - Faculty Reviews, 1996-1997; 2 folders (Box 28)
      - Faculty Reviews, 1997 (Box 28)
      - Faculty/Chair/Administration Reviews, 1998 (Box 28)
      - Faculty/Chair/Administration Reviews, 1998-1999; 3 folders (Box 28)
      - Chairs, 1999 (Box 28)
    - Reports
      - Report to the President
        - 1940-1963 (Box 29)
        - 1973-1983 (Box 29)
        - 1983-1987 (Box 29)
    - Dental Research Institute
      - Biography, Historical Notes (Box 29)
      - Correspondence (Box 29)
      - NIDR Special Grants Materials (Box 29)
      - Quarterly Reviews, 1974-1976 (Box 29)
- Faculty Meetings
  The Faculty Meetings series (1899-1994, 2 linear feet) document administrative issues central to the School of Dentistry. Issues covered include curriculum, finances, tenure and promotion, and clinical services. The volumes (1899-1979) of faculty meeting minutes offer the most comprehensive picture of dental education at the University of Michigan. The folders (1967-1994) contain agendas and minutes that document discussions about significant issues. The material from the 1980s and 1990s focuses mostly on budget and financial issues, clinical services, and the status of lecturers and instructors. Other topics include the development of new graduate programs, department reports and updates, discussion and approval of various policies and procedures, bylaw revisions, introductions of new faculty members, and results of votes for committee appointments.
  - 1899-1912, 1 volumes (Box 6)
  - 1911-1930, 1 volumes (Box 6)
  - 1930-1938, 1 volumes (Box 6)
  - 1938-1962, 1 volumes; 1 folders (Box 6)
  - 1962-1966, 1 volumes; 1 folders (Box 6)
  - 1966-1979, 6 volumes (Box 7)
  - 1967-1978 (Box 13)
  - 1980-1981 (Box 13)
  - 1984-1985 (Box 13)
  - 1986-1987 (Box 13)
  - 1988-1989 (Box 13)
  - 1989-1990 (Box 14)
  - 1991-1992 (Box 14)
  - 1993-1994 (Box 14)
- Organizations
  The Organizations series (1901-1981, 0.8 linear feet) is arranged alphabetically and contains information about students organizations (social and professional), and dentistry organizations both internal and external to the university.
  - Alumni Society
    - Constitution and By-laws, undated (Box 9)
    - Correspondence, 1962-1964 (Box 9)
    - Minutes of the Board of Governors, 1962-1976 (Box 9)
    - Visiting Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 9)
  - American Association of Dental Examiners
    - 75th Anniversary and Annual Meeting, 1958 (Box 9)
  - American Association of Dental Schools
    - Constitution and By-Laws, 1923 (Box 9)
  - American Dental Association
    - National Dental Examinations: University of Michigan Results, 1977-1982 (Box 9)
    - Oral Surgery, 1950-1955 (Box 9)
    - Requirements for Advanced Specialty Programs, 1974 (Box 9)
    - School of Dentistry Reports to ADA, 1938-1964; 4 folders (Box 9)
  - American Institute of Dental Teachers, 1915 (Box 9)
  - American Medical Association, 1931 (Box 9)
  - Children Fund of Michigan, 1930-1946 (Box 9)
  - Delta Sigma Delta, 1970-1977 (Box 9)
  - Dental Faculties Association of American Universities, 1918-1922 (Box 9)
  - Dental Society, 1934 (Box 9)
  - Detroit Dental Society, 1947; 1951 (Box 9)
  - Faculty Women's Club (Box 9)
  - Jakie Jungman Party
    - History and Membership, 1955; 1960-1980 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence, 1960-1979 (Box 9)
  - Michigan Dental Club of Korea (Box 9)
  - Omicron Kappa Upsilon, 1940; 1944 (Box 9)
  - Orthodontic Alumni Association, 1967 (Box 9)
  - Phi Kappa Phi Honor Society, 1927-1958 (Box 9)
  - Psi Omega Fraternity, 1921; 1949 (Box 9)
  - School of Dentistry Fund, 1964 (Box 9)
  - Sigma Xi, 1929-1948 (Box 9)
  - Ura G. Rickert Dental Society, 1941-1942 (Box 9)
  - Washtenaw County Dental Association, 1901 (Box 9)
  - Xi Psi Fraternity, 1934-1986 (Box 9)
- Surveys, 1936-1961
  The series Surveys (1936-1961, 1.3 linear feet) contains different studies and questionnaires evaluating dental education and curriculum. This series also includes a major survey done by the School of Dentistry in 1960 studying dentistry programs in the United States. Questionnaires, tabulations, evaluations and correspondence between deans and professors from other dental schools and the University of Michigan School of Dentistry are part of the files.
  - American Dental Association Surveys
    - Survey of Curriculums of US Dental Schools, undated (Box 9)
    - Survey of Dental Hygiene Programs in the United States, 1961 (Box 9)
    - Survey of Dental Schools in the United States, undated, 1959; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1936-1956 (Box 10)
  - Survey of Dentistry
    - Correspondence, 1960-1962 (Box 10)
  - Dental School Survey, 1960
    - Questionnaires
      - Dental Hygiene Questionnaires (Box 10)
      - Preliminary Administrative Questionnaire, 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Presidents' Questionnaires (Box 10)
      - Questionnaire Clock Hours (Box 10)
      - Questionnaire for Deans of Dental Schools
        - ADA Support Institutions (Box 10)
        - ADA State Support Tally (Box 10)
        - Answers to Deans' Letters (Box 10)
        - National Total Tally (Box 10)
        - Private Universities Tally (Box 10)
        - Sectarian Tally (Box 10)
        - Selected and Non-selected Half Tally (Box 10)
      - Questionnaire on Dental Libraries (Box 10)
      - Recent Graduate Questionnaire (Box 10)
      - State Board Questionnaire Tallies (Box 10)
      - Students' Questionnaire (Box 10)
    - Tabulations
      - Areas Best and Least Prepared (Box 10)
      - Curriculum Questionnaire Tally (Box 10)
      - Dental Graduate of Tabulations, 1956 (Box 10)
      - Faculty Study Tabulations, 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Tables, 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Tabulations by Class (Box 10)
      - Tabulations by Form of Control (Box 10)
      - Tabulations: Michigan (Box 10)
      - Teachers for Academic Units Tabulations (Box 10)
      - Too Late for Tabulation (Box 10)
    - Comments
      - Questionnaire Comments (Box 11)
      - Letters from Presidents (Box 11)
    - Craig Surveys, 1950; 1959 (Box 11)
- Audiovisual Materials
  The Photographs and Audiovisual Materials (0.8 linear feet) series contains miscellaneous prints and scattered negatives of School of Dentistry students, professors, and interior and exterior views of the school. It also contains a set of audio recordings "Dental Series" in 45 rpm on one side, and 33 1/3 rpm on the other side, which discuss care of teeth. In addition, there are three motion picture films in 16 mm format.
  - Photographs
    - Class of 1902 Reunion Photo, circa 1942 (Box 11)
    - Class of, 1939 (Box 11)
    - Crowns and Bridges, undated (Box 11)
    - Dean Machen (Box 11)
    - Dedication of Sculpture, Dental School Courtyard, undated (Box 11)
    - Dental School/Kellogg Institute, undated (Box 11)
    - Dental School Interior, undated (Box 11)
    - Full Denture Clinic, undated (Box 11)
    - Hospital Dental Service (Box 11)
    - Dr. F. F. Drew Office, Class of 1875 (Box 11)
    - Jonathan Taft, undated (Box 11)
    - W. D. Miller, undated (Box 11)
    - Awards Won by Marcus Ward, undated (Box 11)
    - Michael L. Cardell, 1834 (Box 11)
      (copy of portrait; reported to be Michigan's second dentist)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 11)
  - Audio Materials
    - "Dental Series", undated; 4 phonograph records 45 rpm and 33 1/3 rpm
      - Care of Children's Teeth (Box 11)
      - Adolescent Caries of Teen-age Decay (Box 11)
      - Dietary Control of Dental Caries (Box 11)
      - Flouridation (Box 11)
  - Motion Pictures
    - Immediate Dental Prosthesis, W. K. Kellogg Institute, undated; 16 mm (Box 11)
    - Preparation of the Immediate Denture for Delivery by Brien R. Lang, undated; 16 mm (Box 11)
    - Sectional Tray Impression for Maxillary Immediate Denture, undated; 16 mm (Box 11)
    - Composites, 1998; 2010-2012 (Folder UBImum C121)
- Department Chairpersons' Meetings
  The Department Chairpersons' Meetings series (1982-1998, 1.5 linear feet) contains agendas, related documents, and meeting minutes of the Dean's meetings with department chairpersons from 1982 to 1998. Materials document discussions of various major topics in the administration of the School of Dentistry. Topics of discussion include: tenure and promotion, budget and financial sustainability issues, curriculum, enrollment, fundraising and development efforts, current research, research priorities, and maintenance and access to research facilities.
  - 1982-1983 (Box 12)
  - 1983-1984 (Box 12)
  - 1985-1986 (Box 12)
  - 1986-1987 (Box 12)
  - 1990, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - 1991, 4 folders (Box 12)
  - 1992, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - 1992 (Box 12)
  - 1993, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - 1994, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - 1995, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - 1996, 3 folders (Box 13)
  - 1997, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - 1997, 1 folders (Box 13)
  - 1998, 3 folders (Box 13)
- American Dental Association (ADA) Accreditation
  The American Dental Association Accreditation series (1942-2002, 1.5 linear feet) documents the School of Dentistry's participation in the American Dental Association (ADA) accreditation process. The series is divided into two subseries: General (1942-2002) and Specialties (1978-1987). The General subseries contains correspondence, self-evaluations, and final reports from the 1970s and 1980s, an internal review from 2002, and a survey of dental schools from 1942-1943. The Specialties subseries includes progress reports and accreditation manuals for the Dental Hygiene, Endodontics, Orthodontics, and Prosthodontics programs within the School of Dentistry.
  - General, 1942-2002
    - Correspondence, 3 folders (Box 34)
    - Evaluation Reports, 1971; 1977; 1987; 2 folders (Box 34)
    - Internal Review, 2002 (Box 34)
    - Response to Site Visit Report, 1987 (Box 34)
    - Self-Surveys, undated (Box 34)
    - Survey Manual, 1971 (Box 34)
    - Survey of Dental Schools, 1942-1943 (Box 34)
  - Specialties, 1978-1987
    - Endodontics, Progress Report, 1981 (Box 34)
    - Orthodontics, Application, Self-Study Manual, 1978 (Box 34)
    - Orthodontics, Interim Report, 1983-1984 (Box 34)
    - Prosthodontics, Progress Report, 1981 (Box 34)
    - Dental Hygiene, Program, undated (Box 35)
    - Dental Hygiene, Accreditation Manual, 1987 (Box 35)
    - Dental Hygiene, Accreditation Appendix, 1987; 6 folders (Box 35)
- Archived Dental School Website